在上一个视频中，我们学习了堆如何工作的一些基本知识，现在我们要应用
this to heap level 1 from exploit-exercsies protostar to solve it.
Actually I want try something.
We do some roleplaying.
让我们先做一个安全研究员，他想找到一个可以利用的漏洞
binary.
Afterwards we play developer trying to understand the exploit to fix the issue.
所以我们穿上黑色的连帽衫开始……首先我们在gdb中打开binary heap1，然后
execute it.
We get a segfault.
同时也说明SEGCFAULT是由strcpy引起的，因为它试图复制
从地址0到这里的另一个地址0的字符串显然无效
memory - so it crashes.
我们知道Linux二进制文件是如何工作的，所以我们有根据地猜测这个应用程序可能
require some input and we try the arguments.
Run with aaaa.
又是另一个segfault，但是细心的观察者会注意到地址现在是
不同，所以这是一个不同的strcpy，它同样不能从地址0复制，所以
we guess that it requires another argument.
And this time the program runs through without errors.
现在我们试图找到一个bug，所以最简单的事情就是，我们只需要抛出一些长的输入
at the program and see if something happens.
所以对于第一个参数，我选择用字母做一个模式，对于第二个参数
I do numbers, just so I could idnetify them if something would occur.
We run that, and we got a different segfault.
Again because of strcpy, but this time the destination address looks invalid.
它试图将带有数字的字符串（我们知道这是第二个参数）复制到
address 46,46,46,46 which is the hexcode for FFFF.
所以不管发生什么，我们以某种方式重写了一个用作目的地的地址
of the strcpy.
And this means we can now use the first argument to fully control where we want to write.
And we can fully choose what to write, with the second argument.
Now we have a lot of freedom what we want to overwrite.
例如，我们可以覆盖堆栈上的返回指针来重定向代码执行，或者
我们可以覆盖全局偏移表的一个条目，我在前面的视频中解释过，
to achieve the same.
让我们来做后一个，它通常比堆栈更可靠，后者喜欢
to move around.
So let’s check what kind of function is called after the evil strcpy.
我们可以到达源代码的峰值，看到有一个printf，我们可以假设
we want to overwrite printf on the global offset table, but that is deceiving.
That’s not the case.
So let’s better stick to the assembly.
First of all we have to find the location from were we were calling the strcpy.
我们可以使用backtrace，它将查看堆栈和存储的返回指针
为了弄清楚我们在哪里——作为旁注，如果你发现了一个破坏堆栈的错误，
then backtrace can not make much sense of it anymore.
So it doesn’t always work.
And here we can see that currently we are in strcpy, but we were coming from this address.
So let’s set the disassemblu flavor to sane intel syntax and disasemble the address.
This will now disassemble the whole function this address belongs to.
Our address ended in 5a, so we are here after the strcpy.
And as you can see there is a call to puts next.
Which btw is not printf like in the source code.
That’s because the compiler replaced the printf with puts for optimization reasons.
Ok, so let’s overwrite the global offset table entry for puts.
如got视频所示，我们可以通过首先分解找出放置的地址。
过程链接表中的函数trapoline，现在将跳转到一个地址
stored at this address.
So this means this is the address of the puts global offset table entry.
So this is the target we want to write to, thus we place it in the first argument.
gdb run, but we use backticks in the first argument to execute /bin/echo.
正如您所知，echo只输出您作为参数传递给它的任何内容，我们可以使用它
to get characters with hexvalues we can’t type.
For example the hex value 8.
所以echo-ne，-n是因为我们不希望echo在输出的末尾放置新行。
and -e because we want echo to convert hex escaped numbers into the raw characters.
Just to make sure everything works we echo the whole test string up to the Fs again.
现在将执行backticks中的echo，并将其输出放入
of the quotes as the first argument.
And when we run this we get the same segfault as before, so all is fine.
下一步显然是用puts全局偏移表的地址替换fs。
entry.
当我们现在运行它的时候，我们在其他地方得到一个SegFault，这次是因为30303030，它
is ascii for 0000.
当我们用信息寄存器查看寄存器时，我们可以看到我们成功地得到了
control of EIP, which means we can now redirect code anywhere we want.
In this case we want to call winner, winner has this address here.
So we place that into the second argument instead of argv2 by using echo in backticks.
We execute it and we get winner.
Which also works great outside of gdb.
总之，我们可以这样说：我们通过猜测和玩来识别一个bug
around with it.
通过gdb，我们了解到我们可以通过某种方式控制strcpy的目的地，并且我们
learned we even control what we want to copy.
我们滥用它来覆盖puts的函数地址来重定向代码执行。
to the winner function.
都不知道为什么会发生这种情况，甚至不知道涉及堆
at all.
Being a good security researcher we create a writeup, an advisory for this.
提供概念验证利用以及一些可能
help the developer.
Now let’s change sides and become the developer.
We take off our black hoodie, and put on our grey hoodie.
Because that's what developers wear.
So we just got this email from this dude who found a bug in our program.
He even provided a Proof of Concept exploit with it.
Now we want to figure out why and how this happened, so we can fix it.
In the advisory it says that it has to do something with strcpy.
So we read the manual about strcpy.
当我们意识到我们甚至没有阅读文档时，就有了这个“噢，该死的”时刻。
that would have told us what a bad idea that was.
So now we could fix that.
例如，在复制之前使用strncpy或使用strlen检查长度，然后
exit.
但是因为我们是一个优秀的开发人员，所以我们试图从这个建议中学习并理解
how the exploit exactly works.
在上一个视频，堆malloc介绍视频中，我们已经考虑了堆
should look like from this program.
So let’s see how it looks in reality.
To do this let’s set a breakpoint after each malloc and strcpy.
We dissasemble main and look for all those calls and set breakpoints afterwards.
Then we run it with the proof of concept exploit arguments.
And we hit the first breakpoint.
So now the first malloc happened.
So we are currently here in the assembler code and the result of malloc is in eax.
所以eax包含堆上的地址，在那里我们有足够的空间用于Internet结构
i1.
And we can look at this address and we can see it’s simply 0.
使用info-proc映射，我们可以看到内存段，还有堆和
can have a look at that.
Oh, maybe it’s a good idea to add this heap output as a gdb hook as well.
So we see it automatically at each breakpoint.
定义挂钩停止X/64WX 0x
结束
So if we now continue we should set the priority of i1 to 1, and then malloc for the name.
Let’s have a closer look at the heap.
So as we learned the i1 variable points here.
所以这就是结构开始的地方，您可以将第一个属性
the priority is set to 1.
在此之前，我们有堆元数据，即块头，其中包含
包括最后一位设置为1，这意味着前一个块
not free.
It’s in use.
我们看到的是我们所期望的，我们在这里看到两个8字节的块，包括
headers it’s obviously 16 bytes.
我们可以做的另一件很酷的事情是在gdb中定义一个变量i1并将其设置为地址
of this object.
Aaand we can even add the type of this variable which is “struct internet”.
现在我们可以打印这个变量i1，gdb可以显示属性priority和
name.
我们可以看到优先级是1，名称仍然是零，因为我们已经分配了内存
for the name but not yet assigned it to the i1 attribute name.
如果我们继续到下一个断点，将分配名称的地址和I2
object got allocated.
And the result of malloc is again in eax, that’s the address of the i2 object.
So we can also define the variable i2 in gdb.
And when we print that we can see that it’s still empty.
现在，如果我们继续，I2的优先级应该设置为2，我们可以通过查看来验证
at the heap memory as well when we print the i2 object.
Also all of our 4 mallocs are done now.
如果我们将其与之前视频中的预期进行比较，我们会发现它符合
perfectly.
只有一件事我们还没有讨论过，那就是在
all chunks at the end.
好吧，下面这个区域是所有的空闲内存，用剥削的术语来说，这经常被提到
to as the wilderness.
This is number is the remaining size of the heap.
This whole thing is basically a huge heap chunk, and that number is its length.
我制作了一个由三部分组成的关于CTF挑战食谱的视频，其中利用了滥用
this number to redirect code execution.
It’s super awesome.
You should watch it.
Anyway.
Right now the name of i1 is still an empty string.
But this is about to change with the next breakpoint.
因为我们要执行第一个strcpy，它首先复制这个超长的
argument.
Continue.
Now first thing we notice is here in the heap memory.
这些ASCII字符出现了，看起来它们覆盖了很多stuf
the heap.
What earlier was supposed to be chunk header metadata, like the size is now 44444444.
Let’s have a look at the objects i1 and i2.
所以i1看起来很好，i1仍然具有优先级1和名称以及我们传递给的字符串
it.
I2怎么样？
Uh… that looks fucked.
Priority is now a super huge number.
In fact that’s just 45454545 in decimal, and that’s the Es.
And the name is 46464646, which we know are Fs.
And yeah, we seem to have overwritten a lot of stuff on the heap.
Infact we have overwritten the next chunk on the heap after the i1 name.
现在下一个strcpy将采用i2-&gt；名称，它指向一些坏内存并尝试
to copy there the 2nd argument.
Really frckn awesome.
So this challenge showed one aspect of heap exploits.
它不攻击堆算法本身，而是攻击使用对象的应用程序
on the heap that we can modify by overwriting stuff.
And those modified objects then bend the execution flow.
很酷，是吧？